ANAND KUMAR PADIGA

Email: <u>Anandkumarpadiga005@gmail.com</u> Mobile: +91- 8247597720

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Looking to use my experience in the Software Industry along with my expertise at Web Applications which will further my career growth and also help me lead and motivate my team members and boost the profitability of the company.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Having 4.5 Years of Experience in the IT Industry. Development

experience on Java/J2EE(1.8).

Having experience in **Core Java** Concepts.

Strong skills in J2EE concepts like JSP, Servlets, JDBC.

Having hands-on experience in frameworks like **Spring, Spring Boot, Web Services.**

Hands on Experience in Using Eclipse IDE, STS for developing software applications.

Having good experience in ORM tools like Hibernate, JPA.

Developing applications in MVC architecture using Spring framework, Spring Boot.

Having good knowledge in databases like MySql.

Excellent Programming and Analytical skills.

QUALIFICATION

BTech (CSE), Narayana Engineering college (JNTU A), Guduru.

EXPERIENCE

S/No.	Organization	Designation	Duration
1	HCL	Software Developer	MAR 2019 - AUG 2021
2	ACCENTURE	Software Engineer	AUG 2021 - Present

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

JAVA/J2EE TECHNOLOGIES : Core Java, JDBC, Servlets, JSP.

FRAMEWORKS: Web Services, Spring, Spring Boot, Micro Services.

ORM TOOLS: Hibernate, JPA.

DATABASE : Oracle, MySql, Mongo.

APPLICATION/WEB SERVERS: Tomcat, Web logic.

IDE : Eclipse, STS.

PROJECT DETAILS

Project 1.

Title : SmartSupplies PMD.

Client: Shires, Sanofi and Johnson.

Duration: Nov 2021 to present.

Technologies : +

Description:

Smart Supplies PMD is used to monitor and control the clinical supplies process.

Smart Supplies solution provides a protocol driven framework coupled with bi-directional

integration to manufacturing systems, IVR services. Smart Supplies is designed to dramatically

increase the efficiency, accuracy and compliance of the clinical supply process with immediate

benefits including Planning, Manufacturing, Packaging and Distribution, Management and

Control.

ROLE: Team Member.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Involved as a team member in the coding part.

Understanding the business requirements and development.

Developed the business logic on the basis of requirement.

Involved in writing Hibernate Persistence classes and Data Access Object's.

• Involved in writing Data Transfer Objects.

Involved in developing Domain classes, Spring Controllers.

Involved in unit testing.

Involved in fixing the issues reported by QA and Client.

Project 2.

Title

: EPC

Client

: Honda Motor Sales Inc USA.

Duration

: May 2019 to Aug 2021.

Technologies: Java, JEE, Spring, JPA, Spring Boot, Rest, Microservice, Oracle 11g, AWS S3.

IDE

: Eclipse. Server : WebLogic.

Description:

Enterprise Preference Center is designed to support the Honda Motor Sales admins. Admin Tool provides options to admins users to add, update and search preferences. Super Admin can create /map admin and approver roles. There can be more than one super admin, more than one admin per brand, more than one approver per brand. Any one of the super admins can grant access to the users. Any one of the admins identified can create/modify preference for their brand.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Involved in writing Hibernate Persistence classes and Data Access Object's.
- Involved in writing Data Transfer Objects.
- Involved in developing Domain classes, Spring Controllers.
- Involved in unit testing.
- Involved in fixing the issues reported by QA and Client.
- Involved as a team member in the coding part.
- Understanding the business requirements and development.
- Developed the business logic on the basis of requirement.

DECLARATION:

ars are true to the best of my knowledge
SIGNATURE

ANAND KUMAR PADIGA